Hello, everyone, and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
And my name is
Catherine, and today we're
talking about some
very interesting stories.
We're going to learn
some words for stories
or tales, but specifically
what kind of story is Marco?
They're popular stories that you hear
maybe through emails or maybe in your town.
There's some particular story about maybe a
ghost or many different things that they're
kind of hard to believe,
but that happened a
long time ago and people
still talk about today.
And they're scary.
Yeah, normally.
So let's listen to today's dialogue,
hear some interesting stories.
And when we come
back, we'll be talking more
about what these
words and phrases mean.
Have you read all these crazy things
that are going on around the world?
What do you mean?
I was reading about how some people get
tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and
have their organs removed, then
they're sold on the black market.
Don't tell me you
actually believe all that.
Don't be so gullible that
you're just urban legends.
They're just stories people
make up to scare you.
Well, I was also reading
about how some popular
songs are subliminal or
even satanic messages.
If you played them
backwards, can you believe that?
You really think an artist or
songwriter is going to go through
the trouble of putting subliminal
or satanic messages in a song?
Don't be so naive.
Well, maybe you are
right, but how about
the story about how
KFC has rose of headless
chickens, which are super grown in
order to get bigger chickens faster?
Sounds a bit too far-fetched
to be true, don't you think?
Alright, we're back, so let's
take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So here on language
takeaway today, we have some
words that will help us
understand the dialogue.
The first word is drugged,
so I was reading about
how some people get
drugged in their hotel rooms.
That's right, so if you
get drugged, it means
that someone gave
you some drugs in order
to make you sleepy or in order for
you to not remember what happened.
Alright, so he was drugged
means someone gave
him a drug, something
that made him go to sleep.
Right.
And it's not necessarily
always a bad thing
because obviously if
you go to the hospital,
the doctor may drug
you in order to, you know,
so you don't feel so
much pain or something.
Exactly.
If you're in an accident,
you're in a lot of
pain, the doctor drugs you
so you don't feel that pain.
That's right.
Alright, so he was, this person is
drugged and then what happens?
Well, his organs were removed.
Alright, so organ, an
organ is a noun, it's a thing.
Those are actually the things
that are inside our body.
Right, so your heart, liver,
your pancreas, kidneys, et cetera.
These are all organs.
And this is basically
the category for the
part of the body, it's anything really
inside your body that has a function.
Okay, so this is
supposedly this story is that
people, you know,
usually tourists, they get
tricked or drugged and then
they get their organs removed.
Now what kind of a story is this marker
because it's not just a normal story.
Right, all of these stories that we saw
in the dialogue are called urban legends.
Okay, urban has to do with cities, right?
Legend is a story that
may or may not be true.
That's right.
It comes from a long time ago.
Right.
And is actually a story
that is probably not
true that you hear from
other people like your friends.
That's right.
So usually most of
these stories fall under
this category, you know,
they're urban legends.
You don't really know
if they're true, but
people say it happened to a friend of theirs
from a long time ago or stuff like that.
Exactly.
So a friend of a friend
of a friend of mine told
me that in hotel, sometimes
they take your organs.
Well, obviously, that's not right.
Right.
After that, we have
two great adjectives for
describing people who like
to believe stories like this.
What are those two adjectives?
Well, we have the adjective
to be gullible and to be naive.
All right.
So they're a little bit
different, to be gullible
means to believe everything
that people tell you.
Right.
So if you're gullible, you pretty much
believe anything you see or you hear.
Yeah.
So maybe your friend
says, "Did you know Michael
Jordan is coming to
the office tomorrow?
" Right.
And you believe it, then
you're very, very gullible.
Very gullible.
You believe what people tell you.
But naive, similar,
it's similar, but I guess
it has a little bit of
a different meaning
in the sense that you're
not, it's not that you're
so gullible, but you
wholeheartedly trust people.
So you're naive.
You're innocent.
Maybe you don't have
a lot of life experience.
So you trust people
and you can call a person
naive, say, "Well, he's very
naive about these kinds of things.
" I guess that that's
the main key, right, that,
or the main point is that you don't
really have too much life experience.
So that's why you're naive.
That's right.
And just be careful, because gullible and
naive are things that we say about people,
but they're not nice things.
They're not compliments.
Right.
So you don't, you shouldn't really say it
to someone directly, like in the dialogue.
Exactly.
Maybe as a joke, but not, not seriously.
Okay.
So we have the great
adjectives way to describe people.
And lastly, we also have something
else that, how to describe the situation.
Maybe it's too far fetched.
It's too difficult to believe.
So far fetched.
This is a great word.
It means basically that something is
very difficult to believe, like you say.
For example, the story
about Michael Jordan.
Michael Jordan is coming tomorrow,
you say, "Oh, that's pretty far fetched.
" Right.
I don't really think that could happen.
Right.
So something
that is far fetched is
difficult to happen or very,
very unlikely to happen.
Very unlikely.
Okay.
So very good we've had,
we saw five key words there.
Let's take a break and
listen to the dialogue again.
Have you read all these crazy things
that are going on around the world?
What do you mean?
I was reading about how
some people get tricked
or drugged in their hotel rooms
and have their organs removed.
Then they're sold on the black market.
Don't tell me you
actually believe all that.
Don't be so gullible.
They're just urban legends.
They're just stories people
make up to scare you.
Well, I was also reading
about how some popular
songs are subliminal or
even satanic messages.
If you played them
backwards, can you believe that?
You really think an artist
or songwriter is going
to go through the trouble of putting
subliminal or satanic messages in a song?
Don't be so naive.
Well, maybe you are right.
But how about the story
about how KFC has rose
of headless chickens, which are super grown
in order to get bigger chickens faster?
It's a bit too far fetched
to be true, don't you think?
All right, let's take a look now at a
couple of phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Now in fluency builder
today, we're going to
start out with the story about
organs, this urban legend.
Now, what happens?
When the organ is taken, the story
says that it's sold on the black market.
That's right.
Well, you probably
hear this in the news or
a lot of places, the
black market, basically.
It's not really a physical place, but
it's where things are sold illegally.
So guns, organs, stuff like that.
Exactly.
So the black market, like you
say, is not a place you can go to.
It's an idea.
And it's basically anything
that's illegal that's being
sold, like guns are often
sold in the black market.
That's right.
These stolen cars are
sold on the black market.
Also organs can be
And this is a serious problem
because obviously all of this is illegal.
That's right.
So the black market is
where all this happens.
Now, moving on to the
next urban legend that
we actually didn't
really talk about too
much is how many
people believe that popular
songs have subliminal or
satanic messages in them.
All right.
Look at the word subliminal first.
We all know what a message is,
right, and something that's told to us.
But a subliminal message is something
that is told to us without us knowing.
That's right.
So it goes into your mind, but
you don't even know it, right?
So it's something that
a lot of people believe
in because they think
that marketing people
or big businesses are trying
to control our behavior.
That's right.
I would say very quietly,
Marco, buy me dinner, buy me.
And that's a subliminal message.
Marco says, hey, I was thinking
about getting everyone dinner tonight.
And then that's basically a
way to control your actions.
That's right.
So whether or not this is possible.
That's another discussion.
But, so yeah, that's
basically a lot of people
say that some TV
commercials or ads have
these subliminal
messages that are trying to
convince you or persuade you
into maybe consuming that product.
Exactly.
But they're a little bit
different from satanic messages.
That's right.
So that's basically dealing
with Satan or the devil.
That's right.
So the idea that there are satanic messages
means that their messages about the devil,
about how maybe God does not exist
or that you should do evil, not good.
Right.
So they're very dark and
very kind of angry messages.
Yeah, they, I think
they talk about, for
example, I'm not sure
which song it is, but like
by Aussie Osbourne, that
if you play it backwards,
supposedly there's
this message that says,
you know, worship the
devil and stuff like that.
So that's where these
urban legends come from.
But obviously it's either coincidence
or not, not, not true, right?
That's right.
So we've got these messages
that are also an urban legend.
But the final one is about KFC, so
KFC would be Kentucky fried chicken.
And what is the legend?
The legend is about their food.
That's right.
They say that they don't really have real
chickens that, well, they take chickens and
they, they just, you know,
super, super grow them.
They, the chickens are super grown in
order for them to get bigger and faster.
And that's basically that they
don't really even really have heads.
They just, you know,
have some hoses that go
into their bodies and
feed them in in four weeks.
You have a chicken.
That's disgusting.
It's, the idea is, yeah,
super grown chickens.
And so they're basically,
they're not real chickens.
Right.
That's what the legend says is that they're
not, I mean, they really are, but they're
not like naturally grown,
you know, usually a
chicken takes three months
to grow or something.
Yeah.
All right.
That's disgusting.
The idea of super
growing is like using
chemicals to do
something that's not natural.
That's right.
Chemicals are hormones and stuff.
So that's, they use it,
for example, on plants.
You can super grow a
plant by adding fertilizer
and vitamins and stuff to the
soil that makes it grow faster.
Or maybe you have
bigger carrots than normal,
bigger potatoes because
they're super grown.
That's right.
So all right.
That's a lot of great stuff.
Let's take a listen to the
dialogue one last time.
Have you read all these crazy things
that are going on around the world?
What do you mean?
I was reading about how
some people get tricked
or drugged in their hotel rooms
and have their organs removed.
Then they're sold on the black market.
Don't tell me, actually, believe all that.
Don't be so gullible.
They are just urban legends.
They're just stories people
make up to scare you.
Well, I was also reading
about how some popular
songs are subliminal or
even satanic messages.
If you played them
backwards, can you believe that?
Do you really think
an artist or songwriter
is going to go through
the trouble of putting
subliminal or satanic
messages in a song?
Don't be so naive.
Well, maybe you are right.
But how about the story
about how KFC has rose
of headless chickens which are super grown
in order to get bigger chickens faster?
Sounds a bit too far-fetched
to be true, don't you think?
All right.
So all these urban
legends, they are obviously
most of them if not
all of them are untrue.
But they're very popular.
Why do you think that is?
I think people like to believe
these stories, they're gossipy.
You know, they're scary, you get to make
your friends kind of nervous about stuff.
But I think also we don't trust a lot of
these things because we've heard for years
and years and years and
years about subliminal
messages or marketing strategies or about
these kind of hidden messages and songs.
So there's part of us that
wants to believe them.
But the other part is that you hear
it enough, you start to believe it.
Because I was reading
up on a couple of them
and the most recent
ones are about how they
make the connection
about how Nostradamus
predicted the 9/11
incident or how Coca-Cola
is actually the one that
invented Santa Claus.
And even this KFC one where people
just believe a lot of different things.
I even found one, the
urban legend, about be
careful when you go to
the movie theater because
there might be a syringe
or something on the
seat that if you sit down, it infects
you with AIDS or something like this.
So there's so many of
them out there that if
you think about it, they
don't even really make sense.
They don't.
And I understand that sometimes there'll be
one news story like about, yeah, a needle
in a candy box and all of
a sudden people say, well,
don't eat candy because
there's needles in candy boxes.
Right, exactly.
And obviously, one time event
turns into this massive kind of craze.
But it is interesting, especially with
this whole topic of subliminal messages.
I do remember that actually
there was a marketing
campaign that was
banned in movie theaters
when the previews before
the actual movie came on.
They supposedly they had the sound or maybe
on the screen, somebody opening up a coke
can and the smell of
coke actually coming into
the theater and that
was kind of like subliminal
marketing, making people
want to go get a coke.
Definitely.
Well, we used to pump
the exhaust from the
popcorn maker when I worked in a
movie theater throughout the lobby.
There you go.
Everyone smells it.
And it smells so good.
Everyone wants to buy it.
Oh, yeah.
Totally used that.
So yeah, that is a way of like, I guess it
is subliminal because you're not directly
telling them to buy it, but
you are just giving them all of it.
You're suggesting it through
audio or visual or oratory cues.
Right.
And then you have
the opportunity to sell
them the most expensive
popcorn they'll ever buy.
Exactly.
$12 for a bag of popcorn.
All right.
So it's a very interesting topic.
Let us know if you have any
comments or questions about it.
You can find us at englishpod.com.
We hope to see you guys there.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]